gatorsports.com 2012-06-21

# privacypolicy | Gatorsports.com | The Gainesville Sun

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for The Gainesville Sun newspaper and Gatorsports.com (the "Site"). For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to "The Gainesville Sun" include Gatorsports.com and The Gainesville Sun newspaper. 

Third party sites that Gatorsports.com links to are governed by their own privacy policies. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of those websites or other websites to which they link.

In this Privacy Policy, you will find answers to the following questions:

  * What information do we gather about you?
  * What do we do with the information we gather about you?
  * What is our e-mail policy?
  * With whom do we share the information that we gather?
  * How do I change or update my personal information?
  * How do I opt-out from receiving promotional offers?
  * Is my information protected?
  * Other information: Compliance with legal process
  * Other information: Children's Guidelines
  * Other information: Changes to this Privacy Policy

## What information do we gather about you?

The information we gather falls into two categories: 1) personal information you voluntarily supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, register for an online discussion, enter a contest or provide your e-mail address and 2) tracking information collected as you navigate through our sites.

#### Personally Identifiable Information

### Registration for our Web sites

Anyone can view the Site, but a free registration process is required to access the full range of information and services we offer.

Gatorsports.com requires that you supply a unique e-mail address and demographic information (zip code, age, sex, household income to register. By using Gatorsports.com, you are agreeing to the terms of our Member Agreement).

### Contests, Sweepstakes and Special Offers

On occasion, The Gainesville Sun collects personal information from readers in connection with optional sweepstakes, contests or special offers. If this information is to be shared with a third party other than The Gainesville Sun, we will notify you at the time of collection. If you do not want any personal information shared, you may always decline to participate in the sweepstakes, contest or special offer. 

### Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research

The Gainesville Sun may collect personal information from readers in connection with voluntary surveys. Data may be collected on our Web sites, on the phone or through the mail. The information you provide in answer to optional survey questions may be shared, but only in the aggregate, with advertisers and partners unless we notify you otherwise at the time of collection.

### Mobile Messaging Service

We may elect to offer certain text messaging services (the "SMS Service"). We use the information collected from your interaction with the SMS Service solely for the purposes of improving the SMS Service. The information will not be provided, sold, licensed, rented, assigned or disclosed, except as required by law. We will not use your phone number to initiate a call or SMS text message to you without your express prior consent. Your wireless carrier and other service providers also collect data about your SMS Service usage: their practices are governed by their own privacy policies. 

The Gainesville Sun collects the mobile phone number you use to send us a text message and the content of the messages sent between you and The Gainesville Sun. When you send a text message to The Gainesville Sun or via The Gainesville Sun, we log the incoming phone number, the wireless provider associated with the number, and the date and time of the transaction. The only information we automatically collect is that related to the use of our Mobile Services. The Gainesville Sun uses this data to analyze the message traffic in order to operate, develop and improve our SMS Service. 

#### Non-personally Identifiable Information

### Information Collected by Us using Technology

As is standard practice on many Web sites, we use "cookies", Web Beacons and other similar technologies to recognize you and provide personalization, as well as to help us understand, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. You will not be able to access certain areas of our Web sites, including Gatorsports.com, if your computer does not accept cookies from us.

We reserve the right to place a Gatorsports.com cookie on your computer with a unique anonymous number to ensure that your browser does not see the same ad over and over again, to sequence ads in a series and to measure the number of unique visitors that have viewed a particular ad or visited a particular Web page.

For more detailed information about our use of cookies, see the "Cookies" section on the Registration FAQ.

### Information Collected by Third Parties using Technology

Some of the services and/or advertisements on certain of our Web sites (including Gatorsports.com) are delivered or served by third-party companies that may place or recognize cookies or Web Beacon to track certain non-personally identifiable information about our Web site users. For example, in the course of serving certain advertisements, some advertisers may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser, in order to collect certain non-personally identifiable information about your visits to our Web sites and other Web sites. In many cases, this information could be used to show you ads based on your interests on other Web sites.

We do not have access to, nor control over, advertisers' or service providers' cookies or how they may be used.

You have choices about the collection of interest based information in this way:

  1. If you would like more information about advertisers' use of cookies, and about your option not to accept these cookies, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp).
  2. If you would like to opt-out of having interest-based information collected during your visits to this or other sites, [click here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

Your access to our Web sites will not be affected if you do not accept cookies served by third parties.

### Yahoo Ads

Yahoo! is an ad network partner that displays ads on our sites. To improve your ad experience on our sites and elsewhere on the Internet, we may send non-personal information to Yahoo! based on your browser's activities, such as type of pages viewed and categories of interests, so that the advertising you see is relevant to you. Yahoo! also may use information regarding its own users to select which ads to display. [Learn more about Yahoo!'s ad practices](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/opt_out/targeting/details.html), including how to opt out of using anonymous information to select which ads to show you.

### Analytics Technologies

Our sites currently use Omniture, a third party, to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers to administer our Web site and constantly improve its quality. All data collected by Omniture on behalf of Gatorsports.com is owned and used by The Gainesville Sun. The Gainesville Sun reserves the right to publish non-personally identifiable, summary information regarding its Web site visitors for promotional purposes and as a representative audience for advertisers. Please note that this is not personal information, only general summaries of the activities of our visitors and customers. For more information about Omniture's privacy policy, including how to opt out, go to <http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/policy>

We reserve the right to change the vendors who provide us with usage data.

### IP Addresses

The Gainesville Sun logs IP (Internet Protocol) addresses, or the location of your computer on the Internet, for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We use the IP address log in an aggregate fashion to track access to our site.

### Log Files

Log data is only used in aggregate to analyze usage of our Web site.

## What do we do with the information we gather about you?

### Statistical Analysis

The Gainesville Sun may perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of subscribers, and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for product development purposes and to generally inform advertisers about the nature of our subscriber base. We also use such information to allow advertising to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom such advertising is most pertinent. 

### Products and Service Message from The Gainesville Sun

From time to time, we may provide subscribers with information and offers about other products and services offered by The Gainesville Sun, including subscriptions and other premium products and services. This information will only be shared internally. If you do not wish to receive such information and offers, you may opt-out. To opt-out of offers by mail please go [here](https://www.formrouter.net/forms01@NYTRM/DNM.html).

### Banner Advertising

We may use behavioral, demographic and preference information to allow advertising on our Web sites to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer's experience and the effectiveness of the ads. We will disclose information to third parties only in aggregate form.

### User Generated Content (Message Boards, Forums, Reader Reviews and Chats)

We offer message boards for readers in a number of areas throughout our Web sites. The message boards are currently hosted and managed by Grouppee, a third party vendor. Any information you disclose when posting to a message board, along with your message board screen name or ID, becomes public and may be used by The Gainesville Sun for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. Chats are also currently hosted by Grouppee, and any posting to a chat becomes public as soon as they are published online. For more information, see the Terms of Service.

### E-Mail Newsletters

If you choose to receive them, The Gainesville Sun will periodically send you e-mail newsletters or promotional e-mail about services offered by The Gainesville Sun and its advertisers. For details about The Gainesville Sun e-mail, please see the next section, "What Is Our E-mail Policy?".

## What is our e-mail policy?

The Gainesville Sun complies fully with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address without your permission. If you feel you have received an e-mail from us in error, please contact [ online@gvillesun.com](mailto:%20%20online@gvillesun.com). 

### Account and Service-Related E-mail:

The Gainesville Sun reserves the right to send you e-mail relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of credit-card problems, other transactional e-mails and notifications about major changes to the Site and/or to our Privacy Policy. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive e-mail specific to your participation in those activities.

### E-mail Newsletters:

We offer e-mail newsletters. If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, follow the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter. 

### Promotional E-mail:

If you chose to receive them during the registration process, we may periodically e-mail you messages about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by either (1) following the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail, or (2) you can opt-out.

From time to time, The Gainesville Sun may obtain e-mail addresses from third party sources to be used for promotional e-mails. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by either (1) following the "unsubscribe" instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail, or (2) you can opt-out.

### Survey E-mail:

If you have not opted out, we may send you an e-mail inviting you to participate in user surveys, asking for feedback on Gatorsports.com and existing or prospective products and services, as well as information to better understand our users. User surveys greatly help us to improve our Web site, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form. 

### E-mails From You:

If you send us e-mails, you should be aware that information disclosed in e-mails may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information in e-mails. We will use your e-mail address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

### E-mail This Article Feature:

Gatorsports.com readers may use this feature to send links to articles to others through e-mail. The e-mail address(es) that you supply to this service will only be used to send the requested article.

## With whom do we share the information that we gather?

If you have registered to one of our sites, The Gainesville Sun will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address or any information that personally identifies you without your permission. We do, however, share information about our audience in aggregate form.

If you are a print subscriber to The Gainesville Sun and you subscribed either by mail, phone or online, we may exchange or rent your name and mailing address (but not your e-mail address) with other reputable companies that offer marketing information or products through direct mail. If you prefer that we do not share this information, you may opt-out.

### Service Providers

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, shipping, e-mail distribution, list processing and analytics or promotions management. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for The Gainesville Sun, and they may not share or resell this data.

We reserve the right to disclose your opt-out information to third parties so they can suppress your name from future solicitations, in accordance with applicable laws. We may occasionally release personal information as required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena. (For more information, see the "Compliance with legal process" section of this policy.)

## How do I change or update my personal information?

Manage your Gatorsports.com account at Member Center: You may review and update your Gatorsports.com membership or account information and access your transaction history in the Member Center.

There are a number of things you can do in the Member Center to ensure your personal information is accurate and up to date. For one, you can update the information you provided during the free registration process, sign up for our e-mail newsletters and manage your home and email newsletter delivery options. To gain access to the areas of the Member Center containing personal information, you will be asked to enter your password. If you do not remember your password, you can reset your password. If you need further assistance, please contact Customer Service at or [ online@gvillesun.com](mailto:%20%20online@gvillesun.com). 

## How do I opt-out from receiving promotional offers?

### E-mail Promotions

Follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of the e-mail.

## Is my information protected?

### Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online.

## Other Information: Compliance with Legal Process

We may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Web sites; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

## Other Information: Children's Guidelines

### COPPA Compliance:

In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), The Gainesville Sun does not knowingly collect or store any personal information, even in aggregate, about children under the age of 13.

## Other Information: Changes to This Policy

This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. If we make a significant or material change in the way we use your personal information, the change will be posted on this page thirty (30) days prior to taking effect. Registered users will be notified via e-mail.

## News Registry

This Web site uses services provided by News Registry. News Registry collects content usage information and may use cookies in conjunction with this activity. Your continued readership of the Site means you accept the privacy policy of News Registry. Please refer to the News Registry privacy policy at <http://www.newsregistry.com/privacycenter/servicepolicy.aspx> for further information.
